<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Documentation &#8211; Karuthu Karthi</title>
	<atom:link href="https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/tag/documentation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>A Business Analyst&#039;s Journey of Wisdom</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 17:13:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='karuthukarthi.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>https://s0.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Documentation &#8211; Karuthu Karthi</title>
		<link>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Karuthu Karthi" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>The Power of Planning and Documentation</title>
		<link>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/2020/09/10/the-power-of-planning-and-documentation/</link>
					<comments>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/2020/09/10/the-power-of-planning-and-documentation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karuthu Karthi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monitor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/?p=75</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This blog is all about how planning and documentation saved me from unwanted blames during tough times in an initiative.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this blog, I would explain how planning and documentation saved me at difficult times.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>If You Fail to Plan, You Plan to Fail!</p><cite>Benjamin Franklin</cite></blockquote>



<p>Luckily I had known this before the project start, so I have done the following before and during the project life cycle.</p>



<ul><li>Finalized the Project Scope</li><li>Built High-Level Business Analysis approach</li><li>Made sure stakeholders are Identified and planned to get engaged</li><li>A measure of success in project implementation had been set</li><li>Change management had been introduced</li><li>Documenting the Change in scope at every stage</li></ul>



<p>The project started, the objective of the project was to save the time of employees so that the efficiency of the man-hour is improved. Its a startup Business Intelligence firm.</p>



<p>Requirements and designs are frequently updated, that&#8217;s good. because change is good. Even the high-level requirement had been updated every day, it&#8217;s like today&#8217;s update is no way relevant to yesterdays work. But here is where things started to get a little fishy.</p>



<p>Since the deadline was approaching Business Analysis work had been started in a hurry without having proper time to analyze to what extent this change aligns to the scope of the project. </p>



<p>The project had been moving on this phase for some weeks, I started to sense that the project is not going in the right direction. every stakeholder and business analysis team had been working on day and night but the rock wasn&#8217;t moving an inch.</p>



<p>I felt like I and all stakeholders were trying to push and pull the big rock, but unsure of the direction, Though directions had been shown.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="175" data-permalink="https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/blog-rock3-1/" data-orig-file="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blog-rock3-1.jpg" data-orig-size="1919,859" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="blog-rock3-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blog-rock3-1.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blog-rock3-1.jpg?w=750" src="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blog-rock3-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-175" /></figure>



<p>In both Figure 1 and Figure 2 lot of efforts had been put into, But look closely</p>



<ul><li><strong>Figure 1:</strong> The rock had been pushed and pulled in full effort, the direction of different person are different and incongruent, so the rock remains almost stationary and most efforts are wasted.</li><li><strong>Figure 2: </strong>The rock had been pushed and pulled in full effort, the direction of different person are different. But collectively the project moves in a direction. though the progress is little slow this is what should happen..</li></ul>



<p>This made me to decide not to accept all changes just like that instead put those change into a change management process so that the changes are relevant to the objective of the initiative. This made the stakeholders to loose the collaboration.</p>



<p>No Time to think, just discuss and do. Although in this tough situation where I didn&#8217;t have proper time to eat, were sometimes working even on Sundays, I tried to document everything that&#8217;s happening. At some point in time, I even felt &#8220;I should work instead of documenting because documentation wastes time&#8221; but my inner consciousness said documenting is worth the time. </p>



<p>Weeks moved on like this. New Changes today, which is less relevant to yesterday, which is very less relevant to goal and objective of the initiative.</p>



<p>One fine day I got questions from the client</p>



<ul><li>What had you guys been doing all these days?</li><li>Where are the benefits?</li><li>We don&#8217;t have any results yet? deadline is approaching !!!</li></ul>



<p>I tried to explain the number of changes without alignment lead to this &#8220;the rock story&#8221;. They were not convinced. Then I took out the documentation which I did on every day, presented to them. Client agreed then.</p>



<p>The client requested for restarting the project, But they want some traditional methodology to handle their work. I very well knew that it will lead to failure down the line, explained them with enough data and lessons learned that the project will move towards point of failure. Client was pretty much stuck on the current methodology. I felt that starting again will definitely lead to failure again which is waste of time and money for client as well as me. Hence I dropped the project.</p>



<p>Had I not done the documentation and explained the client, the entire blame of project failure would have dropped on Business Analysis. Good that I was considerably good in planning and documentation which saved me.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>If You didn&#8217;t Document it, You didn&#8217;t do it</p><cite>Karuthu Karthi, Author of Blog</cite></blockquote>



<p></p>
			<div id="atatags-26942-5fcd04e96ff78"></div>
			
			<script>
				__ATA.cmd.push(function() {
					__ATA.initDynamicSlot({
						id: 'atatags-26942-5fcd04e96ff78',
						location: 120,
						formFactor: '001',
						label: {
							text: 'Advertisements',
						},
						creative: {
							reportAd: {
								text: 'Report this ad',
							},
							privacySettings: {
								text: 'Privacy settings',
							}
						}
					});
				});
			</script>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/2020/09/10/the-power-of-planning-and-documentation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:thumbnail url="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/pexels-photo-3752834.jpeg" />
		<media:content url="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/pexels-photo-3752834.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo of man touching his head</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://1.gravatar.com/avatar/19c1f0696385db9c21f2f1463791cfcd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">karuthukarthi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blog-rock3-1.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
