<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mindful Eating &#8211; Karuthu Karthi</title>
	<atom:link href="https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/tag/mindful-eating/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>A Business Analyst&#039;s Journey of Wisdom</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:09:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='karuthukarthi.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>https://s0.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Mindful Eating &#8211; Karuthu Karthi</title>
		<link>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Karuthu Karthi" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Why/How I Reduced 35 Kg? How this Transformed my life?</title>
		<link>https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/2020/08/29/why-how-i-reduced-35-kg-how-this-transformed-my-life/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KaruthuKarthi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mindful Eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weight Loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fear When I stepped on the weighing machine the weighing machine said I am 100 Kg. It was the record high in my life. I pretty much know once I pass this border my weight will be in triple digits. I will attract diabetes, blood pressure, heart attack and cancer. That instant I decided to<a class="more-link" href="https://karuthukarthi.wordpress.com/2020/08/29/why-how-i-reduced-35-kg-how-this-transformed-my-life/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">"Why/How I Reduced 35 Kg? How this Transformed my&#160;life?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Fear</h2>



<p>When I stepped on the weighing machine the weighing machine said I am 100 Kg. It was the record high in my life. I pretty much know once I pass this border my weight will be in triple digits. I will attract diabetes, blood pressure, heart attack and cancer. That instant I decided to do something to not cross this weight.</p>



<h2>Anger and Sadness</h2>



<p>I was an athlete during my school days, Sprint or Endurance whatever you take I was a king, if my friends chase me on the game I will make sure that everyone is tired of chasing me before I rest myself. Only if the luck is against me I will be the catcher, if I am one I will make sure that the game is over in 2 minutes. Having such a history how did I become fat in the first place?</p>



<h2>How I Became fat?</h2>



<p>Being an athlete I met with a small accident during my school days which stopped me from running for more than 6 months. Then I got enough time to study, so I started to gain weight.</p>



<h2>Phase 1: Immature Work on Weight Reduction</h2>



<p>I wasn&#8217;t sure where to start the process of weight reduction, consulted some gym, dietician, doctors all advice which I got was drink protein powder, do liposuction blah blah&#8230; Lucky I didn&#8217;t go for any of these.</p>



<p>I straight away started doing crunches, running, etc&#8230; because I want a quick result. Those resulted in Sevier body ache. I could bear the pain and proceed further, then when I checked the weight after a couple of weeks, I realized that I reduced 100 grams. Which slapped on my face I was totally demotivated and I quit weight reduction.</p>



<h2>Phase 2: Less Immature Work on Weight Reduction</h2>



<p>One of My Friend&#8217;s Colleague Mr Vishnu Dev whose mother, father, grandmother, grandfather everyone was a doctor. He came up with a suggestion post discussing with all of them. &#8220;<strong>Speed Walking</strong>&#8220;. Had he not came up with that suggestion then it would have been very terrible for me to reduce my weight. Every day 1 hour I was engaged in Speed Walking. This reduced my weight slowly but steadily, I was motivated when I stood on the weighing machine.</p>



<h2>Phase 3: Life tested my Persistence</h2>



<p>Those happy days of weight reduction didn&#8217;t last long, I was involved in a project where the project demanded me to work even on many Sundays. The project was a terrible failure. I would have mentioned how that project failed in another Business Analysis Blog. But this blog is for weight reduction. That stress made me gain weight again, though I was in the controlled intake. I Tried meditation to relief my stress but didn&#8217;t work.</p>



<p>Standing Back in weighing machine made me sad, but I had hope that&nbsp;<strong>&#8220;Speed Walking&#8221;</strong>&nbsp;will work. But something different happened in my life.</p>



<h2>Phase 4: My Life, My Body, My Rules</h2>



<p>My sister got married, her husband was a fitness kind of person, Nice Guy Mr Sampath. I requested advice and tips from him. Had he given advice I would not have learned so much, instead, he said one simple sentence.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Everybody in the world is unique, the rule which worked for me may not work for you</p><cite>Mr Sampath Nagarajan</cite></blockquote>



<p>He brought me a lot of fitness magazine, asked me to read those and make my own rules as I am the person who best understands my body chemistry. That was new to me. I did as he said.</p>



<p>My Sister Mrs Aarthi Gifted me Fitness Devices, Athletic Wear to motivate me.</p>



<h3>Made my Own Rule Version 1</h3>



<p>Here are the rules I followed, I Challenged and Fought against my body to Reduce</p>



<ol><li>Speed Walk at 6 Km/Hour. Everyday 1-hour walk.</li><li>No White Sugar</li><li>Less White Rice</li><li>Less Maida</li><li>Less Milk</li><li>Reduce Junk to Minimum or None.</li><li>Regular Food, because I can&#8217;t bear my hunger.</li></ol>



<p>I hated my body and want it to be in pain for becoming fat and not reducing my weight. ( I knew it was wrong later, but I shouldn&#8217;t forget the journey of my life). I literally challenged my body to gain weight since I was very sincere in the reduction of weight. Things started to fall under my control, some deviations here and there but the bigger picture was under my control.</p>



<p>One fine day my friend Poiyamozhi introduced me to Basket Ball. Some professional joined the game, my intention was just to keep moving my playtime was the same 1 hour but I ran, jogged, walked a lot, which reduced my weight faster. Faster the weight reduced more aggressive I start to involve in the game. I was the only person in the game who doesn&#8217;t know to play but keep chasing the opponent who has the ball try to snatch the ball from them, pass it to my team expert.</p>



<p>The Fiercefull fire in me made me fight against all my fat, hmm.. Good Times, as usual, doesn&#8217;t last long. I started to get body ache playing. One of the Expert Player Mr Cecil who was Ex Basket Ball Coacher taught me to warm up and warm down exercises. I did those exercise pre and post gameplay so that I am good after the game.</p>



<p>One fine day a spark came in my mind. Those warm down exercises are they yoga or not? I start to watch a lot of videos on the internet then I found that those are perfect yoga for stretching and relaxing various parts of the body.</p>



<p>I deep-dived into a lot of things which changed my life I guess.</p>



<h2>Phase 5: Our Life, Our Body, Our Rules</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Talk to yourself at least once in a Day&#8230; Otherwise, you may miss a meeting with an EXCELLENT person in this World.</p><cite>Swami Vivekananda</cite></blockquote>



<p>How many times have I spoken to myself like that? I then started to speak to my inner self at least once in a day from that day. Which made me realize that I had been fighting and cursing me instead of being compassionate with myself.</p>



<p>I started to follow some of the following</p>



<ol><li>Thiruvalluvar 500 BC Approx &#8211; He is the greatest philosopher I have ever seen</li><li>Dr G Sivaraman &#8211; Sidda Doctor</li><li>Dr BM Hegde</li><li>Ekhart Yoga &#8211; (Not sponsored by the way)</li></ol>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>No matter you are fat or thin, If you can walk full speed for 45 minutes, Touch all parts of your body with your hand, lift your own weight and wake up with the enthusiasm to do something good then you are leading a healthy life</p><cite>Karuthu Karthi &#8211; Author of Blog</cite></blockquote>



<p>With this knowledge, I prepared a killer plan which is flexible as per my need and achieves what I want.</p>



<h3>Made my Own Rule Version 2</h3>



<p>First Priority as healthy life and second priority as weight loss, Adhered to following things on the second version of my rule, Every point below came after intensive research done by myself so much research that every point requires a big blog to explain, which I will do later for sure.</p>



<ol><li>No to White Rice (Eat only when it is unavoidable)</li><li>Replace white rice with Red rice, Black rice, Foxtail millet, Finger millet, Pearl millet, Barnyard millet, Kodo millet, Little millet</li><li>White Sugar = Slow Poison</li><li>No Milk (Consume only if I am consuming Ayurveda Medicine which demands to)</li><li>A Very Good Yes to Buttermilk</li><li>No Pastries</li><li>Strict No to Oats</li><li>Eat Only when I am hungry, Eat Moderately</li><li>A Very Good Yes to Sesame Oil, Ground Nut Oil, Coconut Oil, Ghee, Butter</li><li>Strict No to White Leghorn Chickens and its Eggs ( I consume once in a while 1 or 2 pieces to quench my long term desire which I will soon stop)</li><li>Very Good Yes to Country Chicken, Country Chicken Eggs, Mutton,</li><li>Strict No Watching TV, Laptop, Mobile, Speaking and Thinking of something other than eating.</li><li>Close the mouth while chewing, Chew 32 times on Vegetarian and 50-70 times on Non-vegetarian foods.</li><li>Strict No to Non-Veg Meal after 6 PM</li><li>Mandatory Yoga 5 Days a Week.</li></ol>



<p>With all the above practices my ultimate goal was to stay healthy, Weight loss came to me as a byproduct. </p>



<h2>Phase 6: Journey to Wisdom</h2>



<p>Now with proper yoga 5 days a week and healthy eating, I still felt some ingredient missing towards a healthy life. Later I discovered that meditation is the next step of yoga, where the sole purpose of yoga is to get your mind and body ready for meditation. Back in olden days I tried meditation and failed. This time it felt a little bit less hard than the previous one.</p>



<p>I started to follow Yongey Mingyur Rinpoche a Buddhist Monk, he though me what is meditation in just 2 minutes, the question which I asked hundreds of people during the past decade.</p>



<p>I started my journey of meditation 5-15 minutes every day, by the time I write this blog I was in 6th week of meditation. True meditation needs years of practice, I am no way even close to them and I can&#8217;t even compare myself to any of true meditators. But I could say that I am consistently trying to meditate every day.</p>



<p>I will update my journey of meditation since I didn&#8217;t feel any benefits of meditation so far.</p>



<p>I have also dived myself into &#8220;<strong>Mindful Eating</strong>&#8220;. Every piece of food I swallow I know what I am eating, what kind of nutrition&#8217;s are there and what good it&#8217;s doing to my body and mind. So naturally, I start to avoid eating Junk and Unhealthy foods. I finally reached 65 Kg which was so wonderful.</p>



<h2>Summary</h2>



<p>Started my journey as weight loss, transformed to healthy diet now transformed into a healthy mind and a healthy body. From Speed walking to Jogging to Playing to Yoga to Meditation is my short journey.</p>



<p>I am going to start my journey in Quantum Healing. As a Business Analyst, I should ask myself one question, Does the benefits I obtain worth the effort and time I invest? If the answer is yes, I am going to try no matter how many times I fail</p>



<p>The journey wasn&#8217;t easy, My persistence leads to my success, no matter how many times I failed I kept changing my strategy and never gave up.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>All who fall are not defeated, those who fail to rise are the ones who are defeated.</p><cite>Karuthu Karthi &#8211; Author of Blog</cite></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		
		<media:thumbnail url="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/pexels-photo-2377045.jpeg" />
		<media:content url="https://karuthukarthi.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/pexels-photo-2377045.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scrabble pieces on a plate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://1.gravatar.com/avatar/19c1f0696385db9c21f2f1463791cfcd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">karuthukarthi6213</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
